# Haotian (Jack) Gong

Email: haotiangong@hotmail.com Website: ht-gong.github.io Mobile: +1-778-885-6840Github: github.com/ht-gong

#### Summary

Computer science graduate with co-op and research experience in database and cloud systems. Familiar with methods and tools for low-level development in storage and networking. Excited about exploring all aspects of the infrastructure stack to build cloud applications for performance and scalability.

#### EDUCATION

# The University of British Columbia

Vancouver, Canada

B.Sc. (Honors) in Computer Science; GPA: 91.3/100

September 2019 - June 2024

Courses: Tradeoffs in Designing Computer Systems(Graduate), OS Design and Implementation(Graduate), Compiler Construction, Advanced Machine Learning

# EXPERIENCE

# Max Planck Institute for Informatics

Saarbrücken, Germany

Research Intern - Prof. Yiting Xia

May 2023 - September 2023

- Participated in the design of a novel routing algorithm on top of reconfigurable optical data center networks, implemented the algorithm in the htsim network simulator with C++, reduced flow completion time by up to 51% while improving the bandwidth efficiency by 38% compared to the state-of-the-art.
- o Second-authored paper in submission to SIGCOMM 2024.

# Systopia Lab, The University of British Columbia

Research Intern - Prof. Margo Seltzer

Vancouver, Canada May 2022 - April 2023

- o Contributed C++ code to the "Flexograph" graph processing system; leveraged the iterator programming model and the OpenMP parallel programming framework to speed up graph algorithms by up to 14× with multi-threaded execution. Resulting work in preparation for submission to VLDB. [Code]
- o Independently explored 2 paradigms of memory storage interactions in graph processing systems. Presented findings through written and verbal reports in graduate seminar course. [Report]

# Digital Health Innovation Lab, BC Hospitals

Vancouver, Canada

Software Developer

May 2021 - August 2021

o Built a Python pipeline that modularizes and automates patient data ingestion into the i2b2 data warehouse, reduced size of legacy SQL codebase by 95%.

#### Philips Lifeline

Vancouver, Canada

DevOps Engineer Intern

January 2021 - April 2021

o Prototyped Slack chatbot using a full serverless architecture that pushes AWS CloudWatch alerts to Slack channels, eliminating manual monitoring effort for the DevOps team.

# The University of British Columbia

Vancouver, Canada

- Teaching Assistant
  - o Took on teaching assistantships for Models of Computation (2020W1, W2), Introduction to Computer Systems (2021W1, W2), Computer Hardware and Operating Systems (2022W2), Definition of Programming Languages (2023W1).
  - Led tutorial sections and office hours, averaged 87% student favourable rating.

#### Technical Projects

- UBC AgroBot Design team member 2019-2023. Built image detection framework for agriculture robot capable of fully-autonomous fertilization, targeted weeding, and data collection.
- ED Forecast Selected student project for Borealis AI "Let's Solve it" challenge. Implemented and compared ML models that forecast patient arrival patterns for emergency departements in hospitals around Canada. [Code]
- Course Copilot Worked in a team of three to develop chatbot application that resolves course material related questions. Investigated 3 major context extraction methods that ground large language models with factual truth, mitigating LLM "hallucinations". [Code, Report]

#### SKILLS SUMMARY

- Languages: C++, C, Python, Java, Racket, SQL
- Tools & Frameworks: Perf, OpenMP, WiredTiger, Kubernetes, Django, PyTorch
- Certificates: AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate

#### Honors and Awards

• ACM-ICPC Pacific Northwest Div.2 Canada Site Champions

2020

• Dean of Science Scholarship

2023

• UBC Science Undergraduate Research Experience Award

2022

• UBC Trek Excellence Scholarship, awarded to top 5% in faculty by sessional GPA

2020, 2021, 2022

• UBC Basketball Intramurals Champions

2022